viewpoint.com 2019-05-24

# Privacy Notice | Viewpoint

  * Privacy Notice — General
  * Privacy Notice — Products (Viewpoint for Projects, Viewpoint Team, and Viewpoint Field View)

* * *

## Privacy Notice — General

_Effective Date: January 21, 2019_

Viewpoint, Inc., located at 1515 SE Water Ave, #300, Portland, OR 97214 USA, and its subsidiaries (“we” or “us” or “our”) are committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Notice (“Notice”) describes our practices in connection with the personal information we collect through:

  * Your visits to our websites;
  * Information we receive from third parties;
  * Information you provide to us as a potential customer and/or customer;
  * Information you provide to us as a job applicant; and
  * Information you provide to us as a vendor/business partner.

Please note that most of the personal information collected will be stored and processed in the United States.

This Notice does not apply to personal information we may collect in connection with your use of our products. See our product Privacy Notice(s) to learn more about the personal information we may collect when you use our products.

### How We Collect and Use Your Personal Information

### Website Visits

#### Automated Collection

When you visit our websites, we automatically collect the following information about you:

  * IP address of the requesting device;
  * Inferred geographic location via IP address;
  * Device identifier;
  * Date and time of access;
  * Name and URL of the retrieved file;
  * Website from which access is made (referrer URL);
  * The browser used; and
  * If applicable, the operating system of your computer as well as the name of your access provider.

Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to ensure a smooth connection to and comfortable use of our websites, evaluate system security and stability, and support other purposes, such as demand-oriented design and market research.

#### Cookies and Other Technologies

Cookies are pieces of code placed in your browser by a website server. Our websites use first and third party cookies. We set first-party cookies, and third parties set third party cookies in order to provide features and functions (i.e., advertising and analytics). The different types of first and third party cookies we use are session cookies, functional cookies, flash cookies, and advertising cookies. We also use other technologies, such as beacons and social media buttons.

Our websites use Google Tag Manager. Google Tag Manager is a solution that allows us to manage our website cookies and tags through a single interface. The Google Tag Manager itself is a cookie-less domain and does not collect any personal information, but the tool triggers other tags and cookies, which may collect information. If cookies or tags have been de-activated at the domain or cookie level, it will remain in effect for all tags and cookies implemented with Google Tag Manager.

You can disable cookies through your browser settings (see [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)). Please note, however, that disabling certain cookies will prevent you from taking full advantage of our websites.

##### Session Cookies

A session cookie is required to follow your progress throughout our websites. If this cookie is disabled, our websites will not function properly. This cookie does not identify you personally and is not linked to any other information we store about you. Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to support the functionality of our websites.

##### Functional Cookies

Our websites use functional cookies in order to collect the following information through our third party analytics providers, such as Google Analytics.

  * IP address of the requesting device;
  * Inferred geographic location via IP address;
  * Device identifier;
  * Date and time of access;
  * Name and URL of the retrieved file;
  * Website from which access is made (referrer URL);
  * The browser used; and
  * If applicable, the operating system of your computer as well as the name of your access provider.

The information collected is stored on third party servers located in the USA. Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to ensure a smooth connection to and comfortable use of our websites, evaluate system security and stability, and support other purposes, such as demand-oriented design and market research.

You may be able to prevent Google Analytics from collecting data related to your use of our websites by downloading and installing a browser add-on, which can be accessed via the following link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

##### Flash Cookies

Our websites may use third party flash cookies. Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to support the functionality of our websites. To manage flash cookies, click the following link: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>.

##### Advertising and Email Cookies

We collaborate with third party ad networks either to display advertising on our websites or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partners may use tracking scripts to collect information about your website activities and interests in order to provide you with targeted advertising. Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to support marketing initiatives.

The following organizations offer services that are designed to allow you to control the collection and use of web-viewing data for interest-based advertising and other applicable uses by some or all of the companies that participate in the offerings: YourAdChoices (<http://www.aboutads.info/choices>), NAI (<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!%2F>), and Your Online Choices (<http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>).

We also use third party marketing software to send our emails. We use cookies to track email open rates and click through rates. Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to support marketing initiatives.

##### Beacons

Beacons are images, often transparent, that are placed in web pages in order to recognize certain types of information. We use beacons on our websites, in association with cookies, in order to monitor website activity, such as how you interact with content provided on our websites. Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to support demand-oriented design and market research. Disabling cookies at the browser lever may prevent beacons from tracking your activity.

##### Social Media Buttons

Our websites use buttons for the following social networks: Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Instagram, Pinterest, Google+, and YouTube.

##### Facebook

When you access our websites that contain Facebook buttons, your browser establishes a direct connection to the Facebook servers. The content of the button is transmitted directly from Facebook to your browser and integrated into our websites. Facebook receives information even if you do not have a Facebook account or are not logged-in to your Facebook account. This information, including your IP address, is transmitted directly from your browser to a Facebook server in the USA and stored.

If you are logged-in to Facebook, Facebook can directly associate your visit to our websites with your Facebook account. If you interact with the buttons, for example by clicking the “share" button, the corresponding information is transmitted directly to a Facebook server and stored, published on Facebook, and displayed to other users.

If you do not want Facebook to associate the information collected through your visits to our websites with your Facebook account, you must log out of Facebook before visiting our websites. For information regarding Facebook’s privacy practices, please [click here for its Data Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation).

##### Twitter, LinkedIn, Instagram, Google+, and YouTube

The other social media buttons used by our websites function in the same manner as the Facebook buttons. If you do not want the social media provider(s) to associate the information collected through your visits to our websites with your social media account(s), you must logout of your account(s) before visiting our websites. For information regarding each social media provider’s privacy practices, please see the following links: [Twitter](https://twitter.com/en/privacy); [LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=); [Instagram; ](https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875?helpref=page_content)[Google+](https://policies.google.com/privacy); and [YouTube](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

#### Links to Third Party Websites

Our websites may contain links to websites, applications, and/or services (“Properties”) maintained and/or provided by third parties. These Properties are not controlled by us nor are they governed by our Privacy Notice. If you want to understand the privacy practices of the third parties who control these Properties, we encourage you to review the third parties’ privacy notices.

#### Contact Requests and Live Chats

So that you may contact us with your questions and/or comments, our websites provide contact forms and the ability to initiate live chats (we may use a third party vendor to support live chat). In order to process your request, we need the following information: your name, email address, telephone number, your company’s name and your role within your company, your country of residence, and your questions/comments. Our legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract or steps required in order to enter into any potential contract with you.

#### Online Registration for Events

We host many events throughout the year. These include in-person events as well as web events. If you register online for one of these events, we (either directly or through a third party vendor) will collect your name, email address, telephone number, your company’s name and your role with your company, your country of residence, and other non-personal information. We use the information collected to provide you with information and services associated with the event. Our legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract.

If you have expressly consented or where permitted in our legitimate interests, we will use your name and email address to email you information related to our products, services, and other events. You can unsubscribe from these emails at any time using the “unsubscribe” or “update your preferences” link at the bottom of each e-mail. Alternatively, you can email your unsubscribe request at any time to [privacy@viewpoint.com](mailto:privacy@viewpoint.com).

#### Request for Content

We offer a great deal of content via our websites, such as whitepapers and webinars. When you sign-up to receive this content, we collect your name, email address, telephone number, your company’s name and your role within your company, and your country of residence. You can also sign-up to receive emails in connection with our Surveyor blog, in which case we will collect your email address. We use the information collected to provide you with the content requested. Our legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract.

If you have expressly consented or where permitted in our legitimate interests, we will use your name and email address to email you information related to our other products, services, and events. You can unsubscribe from these emails at any time using the “unsubscribe” or “update your preferences” link at the bottom of each e-mail. Alternatively, you can email your unsubscribe request at any time to [privacy@viewpoint.com](mailto:privacy@viewpoint.com).

#### Online Customer Community

If you accept our invitation to participate in our online customer community, we will collect your name and email address in order to create your online profile, which allows you to participate in the online community. You may also provide additional information, such as your role within your company and address, but it is not required. We may add this information to information we already have about you. We use the information collected to provide you with content in connection with the online program and our products, services, and events. Note that content you post in the community may be visible to others. If you no longer wish to participate in the customer community, you can withdraw at any time by contacting the customer community administrator from within the online program or emailing us at [privacy@viewpoint.com](mailto:privacy@viewpoint.com).

#### Blogs

Our Viewpoint website offers a publicly accessible blog. If you choose to comment on our blog, you will be required to first register with our third party vendor and the vendor will collect your name and email address on our behalf. For information regarding the privacy practices of the third party vendor we use to support our blog, please contact us at [privacy@viewpoint.com](mailto:privacy@viewpoint.com).

#### Suggestions

Our Clearview website allows end users of our products to post suggestions, which suggestions will be visible by other Clearview users. If you choose to post a suggestion, you will be required to first register with our third party vendor and the vendor will collect your name and email address on our behalf. For information regarding the privacy practices of the third party vendor we use to support our suggestion tool, please contact us at [privacy@viewpoint.com](mailto:privacy@viewpoint.com).

### Third Party Information

Where permitted, we may collect your name, address, telephone number, email address, your company’s name and your role within your company, and other non-personal information from third parties who typically obtain this information from publicly available sites. Where permitted, we may also receive your name, address, telephone number, email address, your company’s name and your role within your company, and other non-personal information from third parties, such as individuals known to you, tradeshow organizers, or event partners. We use the information collected to send you content regarding our products, services, and events or add it to information we already have about you. Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to send marketing communications.

### Potential Customers and Customers

In addition to the information we collect if you visit our websites (see above), we may also collect your name, address, telephone number, email address, and other non-personal information if you provide this information in-person to one of our representatives at events or meetings, for instance. If you have expressly consented or where permitted in our legitimate interests to send marketing communications, we may use your name and email address to email you information related to our products, services, and events.

Where permitted, we may provide your name, email address, telephone number, your company’s name and your role with your company, your country of residence, and/or other non-personal information to our business partners who may contact you or send you content regarding i) our products, services, and events; ii) third party products and services integrated with or related to our products and services; and/or iii) Viewpoint or industry events. Our legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract, steps required in order to enter into any potential contract with you, and/or legitimate interests to send marketing communications.

If you access our Clearview website and make a purchase, your name, email address, and payment information will be transferred to our payment processor so that your payment can be processed. For information regarding the third party payment processor we use and its privacy practices, please contact us at [privacy@viewpoint.com](mailto:privacy@viewpoint.com). Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to process payments and/or the performance of a contract.

### Job Applicants

We collect your personal information in order to facilitate your request(s) to be considered for employment with us. The information we collect includes your name, address, telephone number, email address, and any other information you provide as part of your application or interview. Where permitted, we will also collect your date of birth and social security number (or other identification number) in order to conduct a background check as a pre-requisite to employment. Personal information is collected from you, recruitment agencies, referrals, and where permitted, publicly available social media sites, such as LinkedIn and Facebook. Our legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract or steps required in order to enter into any potential contract with you.

### Vendor/Business Partners

We collect your personal information in order to facilitate your organization’s offer and/or provision of goods or services. The information we collect includes your name, telephone number, email address. We use a third party payment processor to process payments that we may owe to you and/or the organization you work for. If you are a sole proprietor, your name, email address, and banking information will be disclosed to our third party in order to facilitate such payments. For information regarding the third party payment processor we use and its privacy practices, please contact us at [privacy@viewpoint.com](mailto:privacy@viewpoint.com). Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to process payments, the performance of a contract, and/or steps required in order to enter into any potential contract with your organization.

### De-identified and Aggregate Information

We may use your personal information to create de-identified and aggregated data, such as de-identified demographic information, de-identified location information, de-identified information about the computer or device from which you access our websites, or other analyses we create. De-identified and aggregated data are used for a variety of purposes, including research, internal analysis, analytics, and any other legally permissible purposes. We may share this data within our company and/or with third parties for our or their purposes in a de-identified and/or aggregated form that is designed to prevent others from identifying you. However, we do not sell personal information to any third parties.

### Rights of Data Subjects

You have the right to:

  1. Request access to, rectification of, and/or erasure of your personal information;
  2. Object to the processing of your personal information and have the processing of your personal data restricted; 
  3. Object to the processing of your personal information for direct marketing purposes. 
  4. Withdraw your consent at any time if processing of your personal information is based upon your consent. Your withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of the processing carried out before you withdrew your consent; 
  5. Receive your personal information in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format; and 
  6. Always lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority (see [http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm or https://ftccomplaintassistant.gov/#crnt&panel1-1](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm%20or%20https://ftccomplaintassistant.gov/#crnt&panel1-1)).

Note that there may be legal conditions or limitations on these rights. If you wish to inquire about or exercise your rights, please contact us at [privacy@viewpoint.com](mailto:privacy@viewpoint.com).

### Security

We maintain reasonable administrative, physical, and technical safeguards designed to protect:

  * The security, confidentiality, and integrity of personal information;
  * Against anticipated threats or hazards to the security, confidentiality, and integrity of personal information;
  * Against unauthorized access to or use of personal information; and
  * Against unlawful processing accidental destruction or loss of personal information.

### Disclosure and Transfer of Personal Information

We are a global company headquartered in the United States and much of the personal information we collect is stored and processed in the United States. We may share your personal information with Trimble, Inc., our parent company, and our other offices around the globe. Additionally, we will disclose your personal information to third parties under the following circumstances:

  * You have provided your express consent to the transfer;
  * The transfer is necessary to assert, exercise, defend, or respond to legal obligations, claims, or processes;
  * The transfer is necessary in connection with or during negotiations of any proposed or actual purchase, reorganization, sale, lease, merger, joint venture, assignment, amalgamation, or any other type of acquisition, disposal, or financing of all or any portion of our business or of any of the business assets or shares (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceeding);
  * The transfer is legally permissible and pursuant to contractual relationships (i.e., transfers to agents, vendors, consultants, and other service providers that serve as processors on our behalf) in connection with our websites and website offerings, our services and products, marketing communications, processing payments, and research and analysis; or
  * If we have a legitimate interest in transferring your personal information.

### Questions or Complaints

If you have questions or complaints regarding this Notice or our practices, please contact us at [privacy@viewpoint.com](mailto:privacy@viewpoint.com) and provide details on your question or complaint so that we may adequately respond.

Viewpoint, Inc.  
Attention: Legal/Privacy  
1515 SE Water Ave, #300  
Portland, OR 97214 USA  
1-800-333-3197  

### Changes to This Privacy Notice

We may modify or amend this Notice from time to time at our discretion. When we make changes to this Notice, we will amend the effective date and the modified or amended Notice will apply to you and your personal information as of that effective date. We encourage you to review this Notice periodically to be informed about how we are using your personal information.

* * *

## Privacy Notice — Products  
(Viewpoint for Projects, Viewpoint Team, and Viewpoint Field View)

_Effective Date: January 21, 2019_

Viewpoint, Inc., located at 1515 SE Water Ave, #300, Portland, OR 97214 USA, and its subsidiaries (“we” or “us” or “our”) are committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Notice (“Notice”) describes our practices in connection with the personal information we collect through your individual use of the following products and related mobile applications (collectively, the “Products”):

  * Viewpoint for Projects
  * Viewpoint Field View
  * Viewpoint Team

Please note that our customers collect and control the personal information uploaded to our Products, including personal information uploaded by employees and contractors of our customers. This means our customers are the controllers and we are the processor. We process your personal information on behalf of our customers in order to provide the Products and services related to the Products, such as testing and applying new product or system versions, patches, updates and upgrades, providing support, and resolving bugs and other issues.

Under limited circumstances, however, we may collect your personal information for our own business benefit, which circumstances are described more fully below. Note that some of the personal information we collect is stored and processed in the United States.

### How We Collect and Use Your Personal Information

#### Automated Collection

When you use our Products, we automatically collect the following information about you:

  * IP address of the requesting device;
  * Inferred geographic location via IP address;
  * Device identifier;
  * Date and time of access;
  * The browser used; and
  * If applicable, the operating system of your computer as well as the name of your access provider.

Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to ensure a smooth connection to and comfortable use of the Products, evaluate system security and stability, and support other purposes, such as demand-oriented design and market research.

#### Cookies and Other Technologies

Cookies are pieces of code placed in your browser by a website server. Our Products use first and third party cookies. We set first-party cookies, and third parties set third party cookies in order to provide features and functions (i.e., analytics). The different types of first and third party cookies we use are session cookies and functional cookies. We also use other technologies, such as beacons.

Our Products use Google Tag Manager. Google Tag Manager is a solution that allows us to manage our website cookies and tags through a single interface. The Google Tag Manager itself is a cookie-less domain and does not collect any personal information, but the tool triggers other tags and cookies, which may collect information. If cookies or tags have been de-activated at the domain or cookie level, it will remain in effect for all tags and cookies implemented with Google Tag Manager.

You can disable cookies through your browser settings (see [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)). Please note, however, that disabling certain cookies will prevent you from taking full advantage of our Products.

##### Session Cookies

A session cookie is required to follow your progress throughout our Products. If this cookie is disabled, our websites will not function properly. This cookie does not identify you personally and is not linked to any other information we store about you. Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to support the functionality of our Products.

##### Functional Cookies

Our Products use functional cookies in order to collect the following information either directly by us or through our third party analytics providers, such as Google Analytics.

  * IP address of the requesting device;
  * Inferred geographic location via IP address;
  * Device identifier;
  * Date and time of access;
  * The browser used; and
  * If applicable, the operating system of your computer as well as the name of your access provider.

The information collected is stored on third party servers located in the USA. Our legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests to ensure a smooth connection to and comfortable use of our Products, evaluate system security and stability, and support other purposes, such as demand-oriented design and market research.

You may be able to prevent Google Analytics from collecting data related to your use of our Products by downloading and installing a browser add-on, which can be accessed via this link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

#### Marketing Communications

Where permitted (e.g., United Kingdom) and in our legitimate interest for direct marketing purposes, we may collect your name and email address from our Products and email you content regarding our other products, services, and events. You can unsubscribe from these emails at any time using the “unsubscribe” or “update your preferences” link at the bottom of each e-mail. Alternatively, you can email your unsubscribe request at any time to [privacy@viewpoint.com](mailto:privacy@viewpoint.com).

#### Business Use

We may use personal information submitted by you to our Products for our own internal business purposes, including, without limitation, for research and development purposes to improve our Products and related services and/or to identify industry trends (“Business Use”). The reports and/or results of our findings related to such data may be used by us and/or disclosed by us to third parties for their use, but only in a de-identified and/or aggregated manner that does not identify you or any of our customers. We do not sell personal information to any third parties.

### Rights of Data Subjects

You have the right to:

  1. Request access to, rectification of, and/or erasure of your personal information;
  2. Object to the processing of your personal information and have the processing of your personal data restricted;
  3. Object to the processing of your personal information for direct marketing purposes.
  4. Withdraw your consent at any time if processing of your personal information is based upon your consent. Your withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of the processing carried out before you withdrew your consent;
  5. Receive your personal information in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format; and
  6. Always lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority (see [http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm or https://ftccomplaintassistant.gov/#crnt&panel1-1](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm%20or%20https://ftccomplaintassistant.gov/#crnt&panel1-1)).

Note that there may be legal conditions or limitations on these rights. If you wish to inquire about or exercise these rights, please contact us at [privacy@viewpoint.com](mailto:privacy@viewpoint.com). If you wish to exercise a right that pertains to personal information controlled by a customer, we will forward your request onto the customer and the customer will be responsible for processing your request (however, the customer may request our assistance in processing your request).

### Security

We establish and maintain reasonable administrative, physical, and technical safeguards designed to protect:

  * The security, confidentiality, and integrity of personal information;
  * Against anticipated threats or hazards to the security, confidentiality, and integrity of personal information;
  * Against unauthorized access to or use of personal information; and
  * Against unlawful processing, accidental destruction, or loss of personal information.

### Disclosure and Transfer of Personal Information

We are a global company headquartered in the United States, which means that some of the personal information we collect is stored and processed in the United States. We may share your personal information with Trimble, Inc., our parent company, and our other offices around the globe. Additionally, we will disclose your personal information to third parties under the following circumstances:

  * You have provided your express consent to the transfer;
  * The transfer is necessary to assert, exercise, defend, or respond to legal obligations, claims, or processes;
  * The transfer is necessary in connection with or during negotiations of any proposed or actual purchase, reorganization, sale, lease, merger, joint venture, assignment, amalgamation, or any other type of acquisition, disposal, or financing of all or any portion of our business or of any of the business assets or shares (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceeding);
  * The transfer is legally permissible and necessary for the processing of contractual relationships with our customers (i.e., transfers to agents, vendors, consultants, and other service providers that serve as processors on our behalf) for the purpose of providing our Products and related services, processing payments, sending marketing communications, and conducting research and analysis; or
  * If we have a legitimate interest in transferring your personal information.

As for personal information uploaded to our Products that is controlled by our EU customers, the data centers we use for primary and backup hosting are located in the UK. However, in limited circumstances in the course of providing services to and conducting business with our EU-based customers, certain personal information may be transferred to the United States.

### Questions or Complaints

If you have questions or complaints regarding this Notice or our practices, please contact us at [privacy@viewpoint.com](mailto:privacy@viewpoint.com) and provide details on your question or complaint so that we may adequately respond.

Viewpoint, Inc.  
Attention: Legal/Privacy  
1515 SE Water Ave, #300  
Portland, OR 97214 USA  
1-800-333-3197  

### Changes to This Privacy Notice

We may modify or amend this Notice from time to time at our discretion. When we make changes to this Notice, we will amend the effective date and the modified or amended Notice will apply to you and your personal information as of that effective date. We encourage you to review this Notice periodically to be informed about how we are using your personal information.
